[
  {
    "questionText": "When is the most common regular decision application deadline for most colleges?",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      {
        "txt": "November",
        "val": "a"
      },
      {
        "txt": "January",
        "val": "b"
      },
      {
        "txt": "March",
        "val": "c"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "b",
    "category": "applications",
    "subcategory": "timeline"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "When are the typical deadlines for Early Decision applicants?",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      {
        "txt": "September",
        "val": "a"
      },
      {
        "txt": "November",
        "val": "b"
      },
      {
        "txt": "January",
        "val": "c"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "b",
    "category": "applications",
    "subcategory": "timeline"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "True or False. Quantity is more important than quality when it comes to extracurricular activities..",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      {
        "txt": "true",
        "val": "a"
      },
      {
        "txt": "false",
        "val": "b"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "b",
    "category": "applications",
    "subcategory": "resume"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What is maximum number of schools we recommend a student apply to?",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      {
        "txt": "4",
        "val": "a"
      },
      {
        "txt": "6",
        "val": "b"
      },
      {
        "txt": "8",
        "val": "c"
      },
      {
        "txt": "10",
        "val": "d"
      },
      {
        "txt": "10",
        "val": "12"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "c",
    "category": "applications",
    "subcategory": "schools"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What safety + match + reach model do we recommend to our students?",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      {
        "txt": "2+4+2",
        "val": "a"
      },
      {
        "txt": "3+5+1",
        "val": "b"
      },
      {
        "txt": "1+7+1",
        "val": "c"
      },
      {
        "txt": "4+2+2",
        "val": "d"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "a",
    "category": "applications",
    "subcategory": "schools"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "True or false. All schools accept the College Board application fee waivers.",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      {
        "txt": "true",
        "val": "a"
      },
      {
        "txt": "false",
        "val": "b"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "b",
    "category": "applications",
    "subcategory": "fees"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "When does filing begin for FAFSA?",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      {
        "txt": "September 1",
        "val": "a"
      },
      {
        "txt": "October 1",
        "val": "b"
      },
      {
        "txt": "November 1",
        "val": "c"
      },
      {
        "txt": "December 1",
        "val": "d"
      },
      {
        "txt": "January 1",
        "val": "d"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "b",
    "category": "applications",
    "subcategory": "FinAid"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "For priority consideration, when should students submit their FAFSA applications by?",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      {
        "txt": "January 1",
        "val": "a"
      },
      {
        "txt": "February 1",
        "val": "b"
      },
      {
        "txt": "March 1",
        "val": "c"
      },
      {
        "txt": "April 1",
        "val": "d"
      },
      {
        "txt": "May 1",
        "val": "d"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "a",
    "category": "applications",
    "subcategory": "FinAid"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "FAFSA is based on prior-prior year taxes. For Fall 2019, FAFSA would be on a family’s ______ taxes. ",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      {
        "txt": "2015",
        "val": "a"
      },
      {
        "txt": "2016",
        "val": "b"
      },
      {
        "txt": "2017",
        "val": "c"
      },
      {
        "txt": "2018",
        "val": "d"
      },
      {
        "txt": "2019",
        "val": "e"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "c",
    "category": "applications",
    "subcategory": "FinAid"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "For FAFSA purposes, a student is considered as a dependent if they are under the age of _____ (unless there are special circumstances)",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      {
        "txt": "18",
        "val": "a"
      },
      {
        "txt": "20",
        "val": "b"
      },
      {
        "txt": "21",
        "val": "c"
      },
      {
        "txt": "24",
        "val": "d"
      },
      {
        "txt": "25",
        "val": "e"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "d",
    "category": "applications",
    "subcategory": "FinAid"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Do financial aid packages include loans?",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      {
        "txt": "Always.",
        "val": "a"
      },
      {
        "txt": "Some of them.",
        "val": "b"
      },
      {
        "txt": "Never",
        "val": "c"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "b",
    "category": "applications",
    "subcategory": "FinAid"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What is not a type of federal funding",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      {
        "txt": "State-funded Scholarship",
        "val": "a"
      },
      {
        "txt": "Pell Grant",
        "val": "b"
      },
      {
        "txt": "Federal Work Study",
        "val": "c"
      },
      {
        "txt": "Subsidized Loans",
        "val": "d"
      },
      {
        "txt": "Private Institution Scholarship",
        "val": "e"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "e",
    "category": "applications",
    "subcategory": "FinAid"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "A student shouldn’t ask __________ for a recommendation letter.",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      {
        "txt": "the guidance counselor",
        "val": "a"
      },
      {
        "txt": "their basketball coach",
        "val": "b"
      },
      {
        "txt": "their older brother",
        "val": "c"
      },
      {
        "txt": "their internship supervisor",
        "val": "d"
      },
      {
        "txt": "their favorite teacher",
        "val": "e"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "c",
    "category": "applications",
    "subcategory": "LOR"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "How much time should a student provide their recommender to write the recommendation letter?",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      {
        "txt": "The school day.",
        "val": "a"
      },
      {
        "txt": "One week.",
        "val": "b"
      },
      {
        "txt": "Two weeks.",
        "val": "c"
      },
      {
        "txt": "Three weeks.",
        "val": "d"
      },
      {
        "txt": "4-5 Weeks.",
        "val": "e"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "e",
    "category": "applications",
    "subcategory": "LOR"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "The student should provide their recommenders a list of schools, instructions on how to submit the letters (online/offline), school’s deadlines, and _____________.",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      {
        "txt": "a headshot",
        "val": "a"
      },
      {
        "txt": "a link to their Facebook",
        "val": "b"
      },
      {
        "txt": "a list of every single achievement of the student’s life since they were 2",
        "val": "c"
      },
      {
        "txt": "resume/brag sheet",
        "val": "d"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "d",
    "category": "applications",
    "subcategory": "LOR"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "For college applications and other professional matters, which of the following is not a good e-mail address? The student’s name is Josephine Emily Smith.",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      {
        "txt": "JosephineSmith@gmail.com",
        "val": "a"
      },
      {
        "txt": "JSmith@gmail.com",
        "val": "b"
      },
      {
        "txt": "JoJoSmith148184@gmail.com",
        "val": "c"
      },
      {
        "txt": "JESmith@gmail.com",
        "val": "d"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "c",
    "category": "applications",
    "subcategory": "basic"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What is a similarity between Early Action & Early Decision?",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      {
        "txt": "If accepted, ED & EA applicants will be required to commit to that school.",
        "val": "a"
      },
      {
        "txt": "If accepted, ED & EA applicants must cancel their other college applicants.",
        "val": "b"
      },
      {
        "txt": "ED & EA applicants must take the SAT/ACT Subject Test by October of Senior Year.",
        "val": "c"
      },
      {
        "txt": "ED & EA applicants have to commit to the school before receiving their financial aid package.",
        "val": "d"
      },
      {
        "txt": "ED & EA applicants will always be admitted to the school",
        "val": "e"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "c",
    "category": "applications",
    "subcategory": "timeline"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What does early action mean?",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      {
        "txt": "If a student is accepted, they must commit to the school immediately.",
        "val": "a"
      },
      {
        "txt": "A student will find out their admissions decision sooner, but will not be required to commit to the school immediately.",
        "val": "b"
      },
      {
        "txt": "If a student is accepted, they will be required to start school the following spring semester.",
        "val": "c"
      },
      {
        "txt": "If a student applies early, they will always be accepted to the school. The school follows the rule of ‘first come, first served’.",
        "val": "d"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "b",
    "category": "applications",
    "subcategory": "timeline"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "A student should put in extra effort whenever there’s a chance. Which option is not a good example?",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      {
        "txt": "Visit the campus.",
        "val": "a"
      },
      {
        "txt": "Respond to an optional short-response question/essay.",
        "val": "b"
      },
      {
        "txt": "Send the admissions recruiter 2,000 e-mails per day.",
        "val": "c"
      },
      {
        "txt": "Send in an optional recommendation letter.",
        "val": "d"
      },
      {
        "txt": "Schedule an optional interview",
        "val": "e"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "c",
    "category": "applications",
    "subcategory": "basic"
  }
]
